

DATA SCIENTIST

ALPER SAYDAM

■ asaydam21@ku.edu.tr

4 +90 544 458 89 36

♥ İstanbul, Türkiye

ABOUT

I am currently a Ph.D. candidate at Koç University, where I'm devoted to advancing the field of data science and artificial intelligence. My research centers around harnessing the power of data to solve complex problems and drive innovation. It's a thrilling endeavour that allows me to explore the realms of machine learning, data analytics, and AI ethics.

EDUCATION

2019 Marmara University

Mechanical Engineering (English) - MSc. Degree Thesis: Integration of Variable Renewable Energy to National Power Grid

2014 Marmara University

Mechanical Engineering (English) - BSc Degree Thesis: CFD Analysis of a Model Plane

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Tensorflow	•	•	•	•	•	
HPC User	•	•	•	•	•	
Python	•	•	•	•	•	
Django	•	•	•	•	•	

HOBBIES



Rock Climbing





Orienteering

Running

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNVEST (Koç University) 2023 - ongoing Research Engineer

IRENEC (Eurosolar Turkey) 2018-2023 International Renewable Energy Conference Editor of Conference Proceedings Member of Organization Committee

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

IST5DAYS Orienteering Race 2018

Race Coordinator

IST5DAYS is an international 5 day long orienteering event

Uzunetap Tanıtım Organizasyon Tic. A.Ş. 2017-2019 RFID Timing Manager (Project Based) Uzunetap is a professional sport organization company

Macera Akademisi 2014-2016

Project Manager (Full Time)

Macera Akademisi organizes all types of events for clients

CERTIFICATES

Tensorflow Certified Developer

June 2023

Using Databases with Python

University of Michigan (Coursera)

Programming for Everybody (Python)

University of Michigan (Coursera)

Data Scientist's Toolbox

Johns Hopkins University (Coursera)

Using Python to Access Web Data

University of Michigan (Coursera)

Python Data Structures

University of Michigan (Coursera)